<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on </title>
    <link>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Malware Analysis - RedLine Stealer</title>
      <link>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/malware_analysis_redline_stealer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/malware_analysis_redline_stealer/</guid>
      <description>Table of content  Introduction Unpacking Configuration C2 Communication Data collected Checks Browsers FTP Credentials Crypto Wallets Credit Cards VPN Credentials Remote Code Execution IoC  Introduction Redline Stealer is distributed through Phishing Emails or malicious software disguised as installation files such as Discord or cracked software. Recently, Phishing Link that downloads Chrome Extension containing Redline Stealer by abusing YouTube Video Description src.
The sample analyzed can be download here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial - Setup Remote Kernel Debugging</title>
      <link>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/setup_remote_kernel_debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/setup_remote_kernel_debugging/</guid>
      <description>Setup Remote Kernel Debugging I assume you know how to install a Virtual Machine and the WDK. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t I put links besides:
 VirtualBox Windows Tools for ISO WDK WinDBG  I recommand you to make a snapshot before starting the following steps..
Enable Kernel Debugging Start the command prompt as Administrator in order to run the following commands. The first one enable the debugging, and the second one defines the configuration to be used for the debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial - Unpack Self Injection Packer</title>
      <link>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/self_injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/self_injection/</guid>
      <description>Table of content  Introduction Overview How to detect the technique ? Unpack Princess Locker  Introduction Malware authors try to hide themselves from antivirus and make analysis harder. One of technique is called &amp;ldquo;packing&amp;rdquo;, it means to make the code obfuscated and unreable. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at one specific kind of unpacking technique that you can use to finally start the analysis of the real payload. This technique is called Self-Injection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suppression des application préinstallées sous Windows 10</title>
      <link>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/suppression_application_preinstalle_windows10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/suppression_application_preinstalle_windows10/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Cet article fait suite à une envie de nettoyage de mon pc. Je vais vous partager la méthode que j’ai utilisé pour supprimer les applications pré-installées sous Windows 10. Malheureusement, quelques applications parviennent à survivre à la méthode (Hello Cortana).
Ouverture d’un interpreteur Powershell  Rechercher le programme Powershell dans votre menu démarrer puis lancer le en tant qu’administrateur.  Lister l’ensemble des applications installées  Dans la fenêtre qui vient de s’ouvrir, utiliser la commande suivante:  Get-AppxPackage | Select Name, PackageFullName Selection du package à supprimer  Lancer la commande suivante en remplaçant le nom du package à supprimer à la place de YourPackageName  Get-AppxPackage YourPackageName | Remove-AppxPackage Liste de toutes les applications possibles de supprimer Important: Je vous conseil de ne pas supprimer le Windows Store afin de pouvoir récupérer les applications que vous allez supprimer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WSL</title>
      <link>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nikj-fr.github.io/articles/wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Depuis quelques années, Microsoft s’est tourné vers l’Open Source en témoigne le rachat de Github. Ce type de licence est très apprécié de la communauté qui à la possibilité d’accéder aux codes sources et d’y effectuer des améliorations mais également par les développeurs car la communauté peut également remonter des bugs. Le seul moyen pour Microsoft d’intégrer les outils du monde Linux dans son système est de passer par la virtualisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
